

## Professional Summary \_\_\_\_\_

I got into computing at the age of 8 thanks to my beloved Amiga 500 system, and later into programming by building custom Ultima Online worlds with an esoteric E-Script language back in 2008.

Since then I've professionally created web pages, command-line tools, React and React Native apps, worked with SQL and noSQL databases, large micro-services applications, automated infrastructure operations with Docker and Kubernetes, converted spaghetti codebases into clean API services and lead a few projects through the software life cycle.

# Programming Skills \_\_\_\_\_

**DevOps** Linux, Ansible, AWS, Heroku **Database** PostgreSQL, RabbitMQ, Redis

**Backend** Ruby, Rails, Elixir, Phoenix, Go, GraphQL

Frontend JavaScript, React
Mobile React Native

Data SQL, DBT, Jupyter, Spark

### Creative Skills \_\_

**Coding** Unreal Engine (C++), Unity3D (C#), TouchDesigner (Python), Processing (Java), GLSL shaders

**Video** VDMX, Resolume, Final Cut Pro X

3D Blender, Notch, HoudiniMusic Ableton Live, Fruity Loops

#### Education

• I'm a self-taught engineer. I learn by reading books and building things.

## **Work Experience**

**Anshar Studios** Katowice

C++ DEVELOPER, UNREAL ENGINE Dec. 2020 -

- · Worked on a Unity to Unreal Engine 5 game remaster.
- · Developed gameplay features.
- Created Unreal Engine tools for game designers.

Codibly Kraków

Apr. 2020 - Nov. 2022 SENIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER

- · Worked on a distributed Elixir/OTP application managing thousands of IoT devices in a renewable energy industry.
- Mentored colleagues new to functional programming and Elixir/OTP.
- Contributed to the backend application providing GraphQL API.
- Contributed to the frontend application written in Elm language.

**Software Mansion** Kraków

Nov. 2019 - Apr. 2020 SENIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER

- · Worked on a React Native application. Refactored old web JavaScript code, introduced a framework for sharing JavaScript between platforms.
- Developed a hardware-accelerated video encoding module for Membrane (media streaming framework) using Elixir and C++.

Contractbook Remote

SENIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Oct. 2018 - Jul. 2019

- Delivered features in a large Elixir / Phoenix and JavaScript / React application. · Designed, implemented and maintained a data processing pipeline used for processing user interaction and financial data. Built
- reports in Metabase.
- · Cooperated in a multinational remote-first company.

#### **Social Drug Policy Initiative NGO**

Kraków

LEAD DEVELOPER Apr. 2018 - Aug. 2018

- · Worked with the product owner and designers to translate the product vision into a product spec.
- Maintained ticket boards and specification documents.
- Set up server infrastructure and build system.
- · Lead sprint meetings and managed the team of 3 junior developers working on a React Native mobile app and on Ruby backend service. The apps are available under https://testdrugs.info.

**Relay That** Remote

**FULL STACK DEVELOPER** Nov. 2016 - Mar. 2018

- · Worked with USA-based product owner on giving the product a new direction. Scoped projects, maintained task lists.
- Refactored a legacy Ruby on Rails codebase into a modern API service.
- Built a new frontend application in JavaScript and React.
- Built a JavaScript graphic composition library using modern CSS features.

**Base CRM** Kraków

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Nov. 2012 - Oct. 2016

- Delivered features in a complex architecture composed with dozens of Ruby microservices, large SQL and ElasticSearch databases, and RabbiMQ event queue.
- · Worked closely with US-based finance and sales teams, gathered their requirements, wrote specifications, lead and coded the projects.
- Maintained a complex SASS pricing service, migrated to new pricing options.
- Built a system for collecting and processing financial data in Ruby, then migrated it to Apache Spark.
- · Built an internal application for inspecting user data and running administrative actions.
- Lead a company-wide localization effort on multiple platforms.

**Social Bicycles** Kraków

MID DEVELOPER Nov. 2011 - Oct. 2012

- Developed an application for processing GSM communication between bikes and a server using ProtoBuf, Ruby, and RabbitMQ.
- · Built an user-facing web application using Ruby on Rails and Backbone.js.

Left Brain Kraków

JUNIOR DEVELOPER Nov. 2010 - Oct. 2011

• Developed web applications using Ruby on Rails and MySQL.

**Freelance** Remote

Nov. 2008 - Oct. 2010

WEB DEVELOPER

• Built websites using PHP Content Management Systems.